realex.ie 2018-03-19

# Privacy Statement | Realex Payments

Please note if the country where your business is registered is not listed, you will require a third party merchant account with one of our acquiring bank partners.

A merchant account is separate from your business account, set up with an acquiring bank, which enables you to accept payments by credit and debit card.

See a full list of our acquiring bank partners [here](https://www.realexpayments.com/partners/acquirers)

Close

This site uses cookies to enhance your user experience. If you would like to review our cookie policy, please click here[X]()

## General Information

Pay and Shop Limited, trading as Realex Payments must comply with the Data Protection Acts 1998 and 2003 as well as the European Communities (Electronic Communications Networks and Services) (Privacy and Electronic Communications) Regulations 2011 (together “Data Protection and Privacy legislation”). Realex Payments is registered with the Data Protection Commission as a Data Processor. Please refer to www.dataprotection.ie for further details. Realex Payments and its operating partners are committed to safeguarding the privacy and security of the information we collect.

This Privacy Statement sets out the basis, on which any personal data you provide to us, or we collect from you through our website(s), our Applications and Services, or our operating partners will be processed by us.

If you do not agree with this Privacy Statement, you should not use our applications, services or websites. 

## Statement of Data Protection and Privacy

Realex Payments will take appropriate measures to ensure confidentiality of all information, both paper and electronic required for the operation of our business. We will take appropriate steps to protect data stored or transmitted against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss or alteration, and unauthorised or unlawful storage, processing, access or disclosure.

Realex Payments is committed to and complies with all relevant Data Protection and Privacy legislation and/or regulations of the jurisdictions within which we operate. We will ensure that your personal data can be used only by authorised personnel for legally authorised purposes.

We will only use personal data in our possession for its intended specific and authorised purpose. Your personal data may be transferred to contracted third parties, e.g. banks and other firms external to us or within our group for the purposes of providing our services to you.

Your personal data will be retained and maintained in accordance with applicable Data Protection and Privacy laws and regulations.

Via our applications or upon written request, we will amend the personal data we hold if factually incorrect, and provide you with a copy of any personal data held by us.

All our employees are trained in applicable Data Protection and Privacy legislation and will act with due care and diligence when handling personal data.

## Information we collect

Realex Payments’ customers are businesses. The information we receive and collect from prospects and customers is strictly related to our customers and the services we provide and execute. The information we collect may include financial and other information. Realex Payments understands that such information is sensitive and takes appropriate steps to protect the confidentiality and security of all information collected by Realex Payments in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

When you complete and submit a form on our website(s) or application(s), send us an e-mail, send us a letter, or contact us by telephone to solicit information about our services or Realex Payments in general, Realex Payments may store the inquiries and their contents. Information you submit via an inquiry is collected only with your knowledge and active participation, and may be used by Realex Payments to respond to your inquiries, to contact you, to inform you of services of Realex Payments or its partners that may be of use to you. Information collected during the course of an inquiry will not be disclosed to any third party; provided that such information may be shared internally with our affiliated entities for the business purposes set forth above.

## IP Address and Device Data

When you visit our website(s) or use any of the Realex Payments Applications we collect your IP address and other information such as the domain and host from which you access the internet, the browser and browser version, the operating system, and type of device. We do so in order to administer our services and optimise our websites and Applications for you and to diagnose problems with our website(s) or Applications. We also use the information to assist in the fight against fraudulent or malevolent use and to ensure a better user experience. We may also employ location services to determine your approximate location.

## Third Party Websites & Applications

Realex Payments may integrate to third-party websites and/or applications (Facebook, Twitter, and LinkedIn for example). Realex Payments will always ask for your consent before performing any activities on such applications. In addition, Realex Payments may authorise third-parties to integrate to the Realex Payments application. Realex Payments is not responsible for the content or privacy practices employed by third-party websites/applications. Neither does Realex Payments control or warrant the utility, merchantability or workmanship of the products or services offered at third-party websites/applications.

## Retention

Realex Payments must comply with a number of statutory and regulatory requirements in relation to the retention of data. Your personal data must be retained for a period of no less than six years following the closure or your account with us, or six years from the date of the last transaction, whichever is the later. We do not sell or rent your personal information to any third parties for marketing purposes.

## Sale of Business

We reserve the right to transfer information (including your Personal Data) to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of our company provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of our Privacy Statement and provided that the third party only uses your Personal Data for the purposes that you provided it to us. You will be notified in the event of any such transfer and you will be afforded an opportunity to opt-out.

## Changes to this Privacy Statement

We continue to review our controls and processes to assure that they are effective in meeting our commitments to our customers. Realex Payments reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement without notice at any time and from time to time, including as needed to comply with the laws and regulations of the jurisdictions within which we operate.

## Accessing and Correcting your Personal Information

Under the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 (as amended), you have a right to seek access to personal information which we hold about you. You also have the right to ask us to correct information about you which is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date. You also have the right, in certain circumstances to request that we delete your personal information. Any such request should be made to us in writing to: Data Protection Officer, Realex Payments, 3rd Floor, The Observatory, 7-11 Sir John Rogerson’s Quay, Dublin 2, Ireland or by email to support@realexpayments.com. The current fee for processing a Data Access Request is €6.35. We will ordinarily provide you with a print-out of the relevant personal information from our current databases, or with photocopies of records which are held only on current paper files. Your request will be dealt with as soon as possible and in any event within 40 days.
